# Paul Kinyanjui

Huntsville, AL 35806 paulkinyanjuiitabq8\_m9a@indeedemail.com +1 256 652 0699

I am a highly motivated individual, with keen interest in machine learning and big data analytics. I hold a master's degree in Statistics. I am a Mathematics and Statistics tutor with over three years teaching experience at university level. I work as a researcher at Niagh Group Limited. I am currently pursuing MS Business Analytics.

# Work Experience

#### Researcher

Niagh Group Limited May 2018 to Present

- Data Analysis using statistical procedures such as linear and logistic regression, ANOVA, advanced statistical analysis tools such as multivariate analysis, parametric and non-parametric tests
- Proposal Writing Development of proposals in collaboration with other organizations to seek for fully funded research projects.

#### **Lecturer in Data Science**

Egerton University
April 2018 to December 2021

- Teaching data analysis using R, Python, Stata, SQL, SPSS, Excel, Pivot Tables, and Tableau.
- Offering consultancy services to students undertaking research projects particularly in decision modeling, hypothesis testing, optimization algorithms, multivariate analysis, and survival analysis.
- Assisting professors in marking of exams

#### **Applied Data Specialist**

Roeck Company Limited May 2016 to December 2016

- Conducting Market Surveys Identifying popular consumer goods, close substitutes in collated commercial data. Administration of opinion polls to determine consumers' tastes and preferences.
- Market Segmentation Conducting demographic segmentation based on factors such as age, income, education, and gender.
- Analysis of Market Data Using visualization tools such as Tableau, Python matplotlib, and R statistical procedures such as classification trees.

# **Data Analyst**

Statistical Analysis Bureau of Egerton University (SABEU) September 2014 to May 2016

- Distribution of the questionnaires
- Analysis of Data
- Presentation of reports on polls and surveys.

# Education

# **Master of Science in Business Analytics**

University of Alabama in Huntsville - Huntsville, AL May 2023

#### **Master of Science in Statistics Graduation**

Egerton University Njoro June 2021

# **Bachelor of Science in Economics and Statistics Graduation**

Egerton University Njoro December 2016

# Skills

- I am well versed in:
- R: Spatial data modeling, data imputation, MANOVA, survival data analysis, regression analysis, data mining, classification and regression trees.
- · Python: Data visualization, statistical analysis, regression analysis, decision modeling.
- Tableau: Data visualization, trend forecasting, correlation analysis.
- MS Excel: Regression analysis, ANOVA, preparation of digitized questionnaires (for use with Kobotoolbox), solver and pivot chart analysis.
- Stata and SPSS: ANOVA analysis, correlation analysis, hypothesis testing, parametric and nonparametric tests.
- SQL: Development and analysis of relational databases.
- Machine Learning
- · Microsoft SQL Server